HALEY SCHAFER

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I am currently a Learning Success Software Developer at Code Institute working with Front-End and Back-End technologies to improve software systems, grow lesson content, develop analytics programs, and support student progress. Passionate about creating a positive user experience, I enjoy working with and adapting to technologies as they develop.

CONTACT

hschafer@umich.edu

www.haleyschafer.com

EDUCATION

Code Institute — Dublin, Ireland

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development Contributed to curriculum during the course Course project to added to student showcase Project code on GitHub: /hschafer2017 April 2018 - July 2018, First Class Honors

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages: HTML, CSS, JS, Python Frameworks: Django, Flask, React Databases: MySQL, MongoDB Cloud Platforms: Heroku, AWS

The University of Michigan — Ann Arbor, Michigan Bachelor of Arts — International Studies, French

2014-2017, GPA: 3.65

SOFT SKILLS

French (C1), Teamwork, Time Management, Problem Solving, Communication, Self-Awareness, Leadership

EXPERIENCE

August 2018 -Present

Dublin, IRELAND

LEARNING SUCCESS SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - CODE INSTITUTE

I engage in the planning and development of the full-stack software systems that accurately monitor student progress on the course and continuously improve the student experience. I also develop and maintain a range of the code base, focusing on data analytics and visualization systems. I support student learning via tutor sessions, developer community management (e.g. planning hackathons), turning student issues with technologies, such as jQuery, or Django into better code examples and other course improvements.

July 2017 -March 2018

Grand Rapids, Michigan

RELATIONSHIP MANAGER, PRODUCER — LIGHTHOUSE GROUP

I created a semi-automated task using OneDrive Suite to efficiently track and report on employee performance, eliminating the manual generation of weekly performance reports. I managed the company's Google AdWords campaign, and I used HTML and CSS to create content for other departments. I also provided risk management solutions for tech-industry companies, improving the financial well being of clients, properly protecting their company's capital investments.

February 2017 -June 2017

Suva, FIJI (Remote)

VIRTUAL FOREIGN SERVICE INTERN — EMBASSY OF THE UNITED STATES TO FIJI

Following protocol, I created content for web pages from my researched material on the availability of local emergency providers in French Polynesia, New Caledonia, and Wallis and Futuna, improving accessibility to vital information. Translating documents from French to English, the material guided American citizens through the process of utilizing emergency resources abroad, under the supervision of a Consular Officer.